A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Asia Programs, Regional Director, Office Files of Peter F. Geithner FA1532
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Record Group 2 Asia Programs Office Files, 1975-1996; 2; 3.04 Cubic Feet 8 letter size document boxes
  - Correspondence, 1989-1995; 2; .66 Cubic Feet 1.75 letter size document boxes
    - Vietnam - Indochina Project, 1991-1995 (Box 17, Folder 103)
    - Vietnam - National Academy of Sciences (NAS), 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 104)
    - Vietnam - London School of Economics (LSE), 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 105)
      "Report on the visit to Vietnam with Peter F. Geithner, 1991" was removed from file prior to transfer to the Rockefeller Archive Center and put into the Ford Foundation Catalogued Reports collection as Catalogued Report 019565. Report can be accessed on the RAC Virtual Vault.
    - Vietnam - Institute of Economic Research (IER), 1991-1994 (Box 17, Folder 106)
    - Vietnam - Australian National University, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 107)
    - Vietnam - The Asia Foundation, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 108)
    - Vietnam - Center for National Resources Management and Environmental Studies (CRES), Hanoi University, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 109)
    - Vietnam - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS), 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 110)
    - Vietnam - National Endowment for Democracy (NED) - Deportation of NED representative, 1993 November 23 (Box 17, Folder 111)
    - Vietnam Ministry of the Interior, 1994 April 25 (Box 17, Folder 112)
  - Subject files, 1975-1996; 3; 2.28 Cubic Feet 6 letter size document boxes
    This series contains the subject files Peter F. Geithner created and maintained when he served as Regional Director of the Ford Foundation's Asia Programs between 1990 and 1996. This series is comprised of three subseries. Two of the subseries document Ford Foundation program activities for specific countries with Subseries 1 containing files pertaining to Vietnam and Subseries 3 containing files pertaining to Bangladesh. Subject files in the second subseries are more general and document the broader program and administrative activities of the Asia Programs under Geithner's leadership.
    Common material formats found within the series include correspondence, meeting materials, notes, drafts, reports, proposals, newspaper clippings, and Ford Foundation Recommended Grant Action records (RGAs). There are also a few photographs and a file full of bibliographic research notecards.
    - Vietnam, 1988-1995; 1; .76 Cubic Feet 2 letter size document boxes
      Files in this subseries specifically relate to the Ford Foundation's programming for Vietnam and other Southeast Asian countries like Cambodia and Laos during the first half of the 1990s when Peter Geithner was Regional Director of Asia Programs.
      Files document the Ford Foundation's collaboration and communication with other foundations working in Vietnam like the Sasakawa Peace Foundation (SPF) and the Social Science Research Council (SSRC). Records highlight the Foundation's specific interests in supporting Vietnam during its time of change including economic development, agricultural development and upland management, reproductive health, and international relations. There are also a few files documenting visits to Vietnam by Ford Foundation staff and Trustees and other organizations.
      Ford Foundation Representative for Southeast Asia Mary Zurbuchen and Program Officer for Vietnam Mark Sidel contributed significantly to the materials in the subseries.
      - Other donors - General, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 113)
      - Other donors - Mellon Foundation, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 114)
      - Other donors - Rockefeller Foundation, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 115)
      - Other donors - Sasakawa Peace Foundation (SPF), 1993 (Box 18, Folder 116)
      - Reproductive health, 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 117)
      - Sasakawa Peace Foundation (SPF), 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 118)
      - Save the Children, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 119)
      - Social Science Research Council (SSRC), 1991-1993 (Box 18, Folder 120)
      - Social Science Research Council (SSRC) - Southeast Asian Studies, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 121)
      - State Planning Committee, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 122)
      - Vietnam Television (VTV), 1993 (Box 18, Folder 123)
      - Ford Foundation Trustees - Edson Spencer, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 124)
      - Vietnam visits and trips, 1988-1993 (Box 18, Folder 125)
      - Vietnam visits and trips, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 126)
      - Vietnam visits and trip - Ford Foundation Trustees, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 127)
      - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia (UBCHEA), 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 128)
      - University of California, San Diego - World Affairs Journal, 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 129)
      - Vietnamese Mission to the United Nations, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 130)
      - Upland management/development - Institute of Ecology and Biological Resources (IEBR), National Committee for Scientific Research (NCSR), 1992 (Box 18, Folder 131)
      - Upland management/development - World Neighbors, 1991-1995 (Box 19, Folder 132)
      - Upland management/development - University of Cantho, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 133)
      - Upland management/development, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 134)
      - Upland management/development - Vietnam Ministry of Forestry, 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 135)
      - Upland management/development - United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO), 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 136)
      - Upland management/development - Winrock International, 1993-1995 (Box 19, Folder 137)
      - Upland management/development - Winrock International, 1991-1994 (Box 19, Folder 138)
      - Upland management/development - Winrock International, 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 139)
      - United States NGO Forums on Vietnam, Cambodia, and Laos, 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 140)
      - Vietnam Union of Science and Technology Associations (VUSTA), 1992-1993 (Box 19, Folder 141)
      - Women's Studies, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 142)
    - General, 1975-1995; 2; .95 Cubic Feet 2.5 letter size document boxes
      Files in this subseries primarily document the strategy, administrative, and program activities of the Ford Foundation's Asia Programs under Peter Geithner's leadership from 1990 to 1996.
      Materials in the subseries indicate that reproductive health and sustainable resource management were major areas of focus for the Foundation's Asia Programs during this time. There is a file devoted to a 1993 review of social forestry programming in Asia which includes a photograph from one of the workshops.
      More specific activities documented within the subseries include the Foundation delivering severance and final salary payments between 1994 and 1995 to local Vietnamese staff of their former Saigon, Vietnam field office which was shut in 1975 ahead of the Fall of Saigon. A photograph of Geithner meeting with the former staff members and the spouses of former staff members in 1994 is included in the subseries.
      There is also a set of bibliographic notecards for research on Asia. The notecards are alphabetically arranged by subject and then author. They include the author, title, and date information of the resources.
      - Asia Regional Program Budget - Grant proposals, program reviews, grant lists, projections, 1989-1994 (Box 20, Folder 143-144)
      - Asia research - Bibliography notecards (A-Z), undated (Box 20, Folder 145)
      - 1995 Program Division Biennial Program Review, 1993-1995 (Box 20, Folder 146-147)
      - 1995 Program Division Biennial Program Review - Susan Berresford 1994 memo, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 148)
      - 1995 Program Division Biennial Program Review - Field Office Representatives' notes, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 149)
      - Council on Foreign Relations (CFR) Asia Program, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 150-152)
      - Payments to former local staff - Saigon, Vietnam Field Office, 1975-1995 (Box 21, Folder 153-154)
        File contains 3 copies of the same still image. The photograph shows Peter Geithner meeting with former local Vietnamese staff members of the Ford Foundation's Saigon, Vietnam Field Office as well as spouses of former staff. The photograph is dated March 30, 1994 and was taken at the Ho Chi Minh City External Relations Office. A caption is included on the back of one of the copies. It describes who is who in the photograph. Correspondence in the file shows that Geithner sent a copy of this photograph to everyone depicted within it.
      - Payments to former local staff - Saigon, Vietnam Field Office Receipt and Release forms, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 175)
        Conditions Governing Access
        Restricted – confidential material
      - People Power in the Provinces? NGOs and Politics after the Local Government Code's Promulgation, Terrence George, 1994 March (Box 21, Folder 155)
        This report is available in the Ford Foundation Catalogued Reports collection as Catalogued Report 012845 and can be accessed on the RAC Virtual Vault.
      - Recruitment - Asia Programs program officers and representatives, 1991-1994 (Box 21, Folder 156)
      - Social Forestry in Asia Review, 1989-1993 (Box 22, Folder 157-158)
        Related Materials
        File contains a still image of participants of Community Forestry in Asia, February 1993. The photograph was taken at the Lake Palace Hotel in Udaipur, India. A caption on the back of the photo describes who is who. Peter Geithner is one of the people captured in the photograph.
      - Staff - Alsop, Ruth, 1990-1994 (Box 23, Folder 159)
        Restricted – Personnel – Open in 2065
      - Staff - Balakrishnan, Radhika, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 160)
      - Staff - Wollenberg, Eva, 1991-1994 (Box 22, Folder 161)
      - Vietnam and Asia Programs Regional Office files - General correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 162)
      - Women at Work in Mali: The Case of the Markala Cooperative, Susan Caughman, 1980 November (Box 22, Folder 163)
        This report is available in the Ford Foundation Catalogued Reports collection as Catalogued Report 007016 and can be accessed on the RAC Virtual Vault.
    - Bangladesh, 1991-1996; 3; .57 Cubic Feet 1.5 letter size document boxes
      Files in this subseries provide small insight into the operations of the Ford Foundation's Dhaka, Bangladesh Field Office in the 1990s. The subseries primarily consists of correspondence, Dhaka Office policy materials, papers, and trip reports.
      Some of the correspondence in the subseries discusses plans for the closure of the Ford Foundation's Dhaka Office in 1997 and the political situation in the country during the mid-1990s. Geithner's trips to Bangladesh in 1992 and 1994 are documented within the subseries.
      Raymond Offenheiser served as Representative for Bangladesh during this time, and his correspondence appears frequently within the subseries.
      - Bangladesh April 17-23, 1994 trip (Box 22, Folder 164)
      - Dhaka Office correspondence - Office closure and program interests, 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 165)
      - Livelihood, Employment, and Income-Generation (LEIG) Bangladesh program review, Marshall A. Bear and Jennefer Sebstad, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 166)
      - Terms and Conditions of Employment for Regular Local Staff of the Ford Foundation in Bangladesh, 1992-1993 (Box 22, Folder 167)
      - Dhaka Office Administrative Procedures Manual, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 168)
      - Streamlining administrative systems - Grants management, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 169)
      - Doris Capistrano strategy paper - Community fisheries management in Bangladesh, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 170)
      - September 1992 Ford Foundation Trustees' Meeting - Bangladesh Program Overview discussion paper (Box 23, Folder 171)
      - Report to the Ford Foundation Dhaka Office on Support for Human Resource Development Through Degree and Non-Degree Training Awards, Gerard Rixhon, 1993 August 24 (Box 23, Folder 172)
      - Terms and Conditions of Employment for Regular Fulltime Local Staff of the Ford Foundation's Visitors Flats in Bangladesh, 1992 October 1 (Box 23, Folder 173)
      - Bangladesh April 13-16, 1992 trip, 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 174)